{"name": "ST2  1997", "questions": [{"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "1.  A stone is a unit of weight equivalent to 14 pounds. If a person weighs 177 pounds, how many stone, to the nearest tenth, does this person weigh?", "choices": {"A": " 247.8", "B": " 126.4", "C": " 79.1", "D": " 12.6", "E": " 7.9"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "2.  To keep up with rising expenses, a motel manager needs to raise the $30.00 room rate by 18%. What will be the new rate?", "choices": {"A": " $30.18", "B": " $31.80", "C": " $33.00", "D": " $35.40", "E": " $48.00"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "3.  Contributions to a charity are made by each of 5 companies as indicated in the table below.What is the average of the contributions made by the 5 companies?", "choices": {"A": " $187.50", "B": " $210.00", "C": " $250.00", "D": " $262.50", "E": " $350.00"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "4.  Car A travels 60 miles per hour for  hours; Car B travels 40 miles per hour for 2 hours. What is the difference between the number of miles traveled by Car A and the number of miles traveled by Car B?", "choices": {"A": " 0", "B": " 10", "C": " 80", "D": " 90", "E": " 170"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "5.  Which of the following is a value of t for which (t - 3)(t + 2) = 0 ?", "choices": {"A": " 2", "B": " 3", "C": " 5", "D": " 6", "E": " 7"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "6.  In the parallelogram ABCD shown below, AD is 6 inches long. If the parallelogram's perimeter is 34 inches, how many inches long is AB?", "choices": {"A": " 28", "B": " 22", "C": " 17", "D": " 11", "E": " "}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "7.  If the measure of each interior angle in a regular polygon is 90\u00b0, how many sides does the polygon have?", "choices": {"A": " 3", "B": " 4", "C": " 6", "D": " 8", "E": " 12"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "8.   For all nonzero r, t, and z values, ?", "choices": {"A": " ", "B": " ", "C": " ", "D": "", "E": " "}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "9.  In the figure below, X and Y lie on the sides of \u0394ABC, and XY is parallel to AB. What is the measure of \u2220C?", "choices": {"A": " 105\u00b0", "B": " 115\u00b0", "C": " 125\u00b0", "D": " 135\u00b0", "E": " 150\u00b0"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "10.  |3| \u00b7 |2| = ?", "choices": {"A": " -6", "B": " -5", "C": " -1", "D": " 5", "E": " 6"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "11.  A TV station conducted a telephone poll seeking viewers' reactions to a new show. Of the 750 people who answered, 500 liked the new show, 100 disliked it, and the rest were undecided. What percent of thosewho answered were undecided about the new show?", "choices": {"A": " 20%", "B": " 25%", "C": " ", "D": " 80%", "E": " 150%"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "12.  Two whole numbers have a greatest common factor of 6 and a least common multiple of 36. Which of the following pairs of whole numbers will satisfy the given conditions?", "choices": {"A": " 4 and 9", "B": " 9 and 12", "C": " 12 and 15", "D": " 12 and 18", "E": " 18 and 24"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "13.  If x = -2 and y = 3, then x3y + xy3 = ?", "choices": {"A": " -30", "B": " -36", "C": " -48", "D": " -78", "E": " -108"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "14.  How many units long is 1 side of a square with perimeter 20c - 12 units?", "choices": {"A": " 20c - 12", "B": " 20c - 3", "C": " 8c", "D": " 5c - 12", "E": " 5c - 3"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "15.  If (x + k)2 = x2 + 22x + k2 for all real numbers x, then k = ?", "choices": {"A": " 11", "B": " 22", "C": " 44", "D": " 88", "E": " 176"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "16.  Before his interview, Ben bought 1 suit and 2 shirts, all on sale. The suit, regularly $260, was 20% off, and the shirts, regularly $30 each, were 30% off. What was thetotal price of the 3 items Ben bought?\uff08Note: Assume there is no sales tax.)", "choices": {"A": " $220", "B": " $229", "C": " $240", "D": " $250", "E": " $270"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "17.  Which of the following expressions gives the slope of the line connecting the points (6,8) and (-4,-10) in the standard (x,y) coordinate plane?", "choices": {"A": " ", "B": " ", "C": " ", "D": " ", "E": " "}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "18. In the standard (x,y) coordinate plane, how many times does the graph of y = (x + 1)(x - 2)(x + 3)(x + 4) intersect the x-axis?", "choices": {"A": " 10", "B": " 6", "C": " 4", "D": " 3", "E": " 1"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "19.  Which of the following is a simplified version equivalent to ", "choices": {"A": " ", "B": " ", "C": " 1", "D": " 2", "E": " "}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "20.  Four students about to purchase concert tickets for\uff0418.50 for each ticket discover that they may purchase a block of 5 tickets for $80.00. How much would each of the 4 save if they can get a fifth person to join them and the 5 people equally divide the price of the 5-ticket block?", "choices": {"A": " $1.50", "B": " $2.50", "C": " $3.13", "D": " $10.00", "E": " $12.50"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "21.  What is the sum of the polynomials 3a2b + 2a2b2 and -ab2 + a2b2?", "choices": {"A": " 3a2b - ab2 + 3a2b2", "B": " 3a2b - ab2 + 2a2b2", "C": " 2a2b + 3a2b2", "D": " 2a2b3 + 2a4b4", "E": " -3a3b3 + 2a4b4"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "22.  An object 4 feet tall casts a 3-foot shadow when the angle of elevation of the sun is \u03b8 (see figure below). What is tan(\u03b8) ?", "choices": {"A": " ", "B": " 1", "C": " ", "D": " 7", "E": " 12"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "23.  Mary was x years old 10 years ago. How old will she be 6 years from now?", "choices": {"A": " x + 6", "B": " (x - 10) + 6", "C": " (x + 10) - 6", "D": " (x - 10) - 6", "E": " (x + 10) + 6"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "24.  Which of the following is a factor of x2 - 5x - 6?", "choices": {"A": " (x - 1)", "B": " (x + 2)", "C": " (x - 2)", "D": " (x - 3)", "E": " (x - 6)"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "25.  What is the length, in centimeters (cm), of the hypotenuse of a right triangle with legs measuring 5 cm and 12 cm?", "choices": {"A": " 7", "B": " 13", "C": " 17", "D": " ", "E": " "}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "26.  Which of the following expressions is a simplified form of (-2a5)2?", "choices": {"A": "-4a10", "B": " -4a7", "C": " -2a10", "D": " 4a7 ", "E": " 4a10 "}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "27.  The specific gravity of a substance is the ratio of the weight of the substance to the weight of an equal volume of water. If 1 cubic foot of water weighs 62.5 pounds, what is the specific gravity of a liquid that weighs 125 pounds per cubic foot?", "choices": {"A": " 1", "B": " 1.25", "C": " 2", "D": " 6.25", "E": " 125"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "28.   If 2x + 1 = -3, what is the value of x2 - 3x?", "choices": {"A": " -10", "B": " -2", "C": " 2", "D": " 5", "E": " 10"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "29.  Which of the following is the graph of the solution set for 3(2 + x) &lt; 3?", "choices": {"A": " ", "B": " ", "C": " ", "D": " ", "E": " "}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "30.  Which of the following equations has y varying directly as the square of w and inversely as the cube of t?", "choices": {"A": " ", "B": " ", "C": " ", "D": " ", "E": " "}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "31.  Points A(-3,-4) and B(7,-2) determine line segment AB in the standard (x,y) coordinate plane. If the midpoint of AB is (a,-3), what is the value of a?", "choices": {"A": " 2", "B": " -4", "C": " 4", "D": " -5", "E": " 5"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "32.  If the graphs of y = 2x and y = mx +1 are parallel in the standard (x,y) coordinate plane, then m=?", "choices": {"A": " -1", "B": " 0", "C": " ", "D": " 1", "E": " 2"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "33.  When 4 times x is increased by 7, the result is less than 19. Which of the following is a graph of the real numbers x that satisfy this relationship?", "choices": {"A": " ", "B": " ", "C": " ", "D": " ", "E": " "}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "34.  It costs 90 cents to purchase x apples and 68 cents to purchase y oranges. Which of the following is an expression for the cost, in cents, of 5 apples and 7 oranges?", "choices": {"A": " ", "B": " ", "C": " ", "D": " ", "E": " "}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "35.  When graphed in the standard (x,y) coordinate plane, 3 points from among (-12,3), (-8,2), (-3,2), (1,2), and (5,1) lie on the same side of the line y + x = 0. Which 3 points are they?", "choices": {"A": " (-12,3), (-8,2), (-3,2)", "B": " (-12,3), (-8,2), (1,2)", "C": " (-12,3), (-3,2), (5,1)", "D": " (-12,3), (1,2), (5,1)", "E": " (-3,2), (1,2), (5,1)"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "36.  What is the cosine of angle A in right triangle \u0394ABC below?", "choices": {"A": " ", "B": " ", "C": " ", "D": " ", "E": " "}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "37.  The graph of the solution set for the system of linear equations below is a single line in the standard (x,y) coordinate plane.18x - 30y = 546x + ky = 18What must be the value of k?", "choices": {"A": " -10", "B": " -6", "C": " ", "D": " ", "E": " 3"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "38.  Doctors use the term maximum heart rate (MHR) when referring to the quantity found by starting with 220 beats per minute and subtracting 1 beat per minute for each year of a person's age. Doctors recommend exercising 3 or 4 times each week for at least 20 minutes with your heart rate increased from its resting heart rate (RHR) to its training heart rate (THR), whereTHR = RHR + .65(MHR - RHR)Which of the following is closest to the THR of a 43-year-old person whose RHR is 54 beats per minute?", "choices": {"A": " 197", "B": " 169", "C": " 162", "D": " 134", "E": " 80"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "39.  Martina's teacher told her to be sure NOT to calculate (a + b)2 as a2 + b2. But Martina thinks that sometimes that calculation works. After working for a while, she shows that (a + b)2 equals a2 + b2 if and only if:", "choices": {"A": " a = 0", "B": " b = 0", "C": " a = 0 and b = 0", "D": " a = 0 or b = 0", "E": " a and b have the same sign"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "40.  In the figure below, CD is an altitude of equilateral triangle \u0394ABC. If CD is  units long, how many units long is AC?", "choices": {"A": " ", "B": " 6", "C": " 12", "D": " ", "E": " 36"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "41. What is the perimeter, in feet (ft), of the figure below?", "choices": {"A": "60", "B": "75", "C": "80", "D": "130", "E": "364"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "42. Right triangle \u25b3ABC is inscribed in a circle with center M, shown below, and C can be any point on the circle other than A or B. Which of the following is the most direct explanation of why \u25b3MCA is isosceles?", "choices": {"A": "2 sides are radii of the circle", "B": "Side-angle-side congruence", "C": "Angle-side-angle congruence", "D": "Angle-angle-angle similarity", "E": "The Pythagorean theorem"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "43. A square 2 feet on a side is cut out of a circle with radius 10 feet as shown in the figure below. Which of the following expressions gives the area of the shaded region, in square feet?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "44. The inside dimensions of a rectangular picture frame are   inches by 24 inches and the outside dimen\u001fsions are 20 inches by  inches, as shown below.What is the width (w), in inches, of the picture frame?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "2", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "45. The area of a rectangular floor is 170 square feet. The length of the floor is 3 feet less than twice the width. How many feet wide is the floor?", "choices": {"A": "8.5", "B": "10", "C": "14", "D": "15", "E": "17"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "46. For the area of a square to double, the new side lengths must be the old side lengths multiplied by:", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "2", "C": "4", "D": "", "E": "8"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "47. If logx81 = 4, then x = ?", "choices": {"A": "3", "B": "9", "C": "", "D": "", "E": "814"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "48. If A =  and B = , then A - B = ?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "50. The ratio of the lengths of the sides of a right triangle is 1::2. What is the sine of the triangle's smallest angle?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": "1"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "51. What is the amplitude of the graph of the equation y + 2 = 3 sin(4) ?(Note: The amplitude is \u00a7 the difference between the maximum and the mininium values of y.)", "choices": {"A": "2", "B": "3", "C": "4", "D": "5", "E": "6"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "52. Each of the following determines a unique plane in 3-dimensional Euclidean space EXCEPT:", "choices": {"A": "1 line and 1 point NOT on the line.", "B": "2 distinct parallel lines.", "C": "2 intersecting perpendicular lines.", "D": "2 lines intersecting in more than 1 point.", "E": "3 distinct points NOT on the same line."}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "53. The measure of the vertex angle of an isosceles tri\u001fangle is (x - 20)\u00b0. The base angles each measure (2x + 30)\u00b0. What is the measure in degrees of one of the base angles?", "choices": {"A": "8\u00b0", "B": "28\u00b0", "C": "", "D": "", "E": "86\u00b0"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "54. In decorating baskets for a retirement party, Rudy needs the following amounts of ribbon for each basket:number of ribbons: 5; 3; 2length(inches): 8; 16; 10If the ribbon costs $0.98 per yard, which of the fol\u001flowing would be the approximate cost of ribbon for 10 baskets?(Note: 1 yard = 36 inches)", "choices": {"A": "$ 3", "B": "$ 9", "C": "$ 30", "D": "$ 35", "E": "$ 90"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "55. The formula for the surface area (S) of a rectangular solid (shown below) is S = 2lw + 2lh + 2wh, where l represents the length, w the width, and h the height of the solid. Doubling each of the dimensions (l, w, and h) will increase the surface area to how many times its original size?", "choices": {"A": "2", "B": "4", "C": "6", "D": "8", "E": "24"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "56.  The average of a set of five integers is 16. When a sixth number is included in the set, the average of the set increases to 18. What is the sixth number?", "choices": {"A": "18", "B": "20", "C": "21", "D": "24", "E": "28"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "57. Which of the following is an equation of the largest circle that can be inscribed in the ellipse with equation ?", "choices": {"A": "(x - 1)2 + (y + 3)2 = 144", "B": "(x - 1)2 + (y + 3)2 = 16", "C": "(x - 1)2 + (y + 3)2 = 9", "D": "x2 + y2 = 16", "E": "x2 + y2 = 9"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "58. One of the graphs below is that of y = Ax3, where A is a constant. Which one?", "choices": {"A": " ", "B": " ", "C": " ", "D": " ", "E": " "}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "59. How many points do the graphs of all 3 of the fol\u001flowing equations have in common?-x = y - 3- x = -y - 33x = -3y + 2", "choices": {"A": "0", "B": "1", "C": "2", "D": "3", "E": "Infinitely many"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "60. In 3 fair coin tosses, what is the probability of obtaining exactly 2 tails?(Note: In a fair coin toss the 2 outcomes, heads and tails, are equally likely.)", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "B"}]}